Is there any legal reason why sentence should not be pronounced?
- No,your honour. - Yes,I've something to say.
You can put me away,but you can't put away...
what's going to happen to you and to this whole country...
Next time,we're going to...
Do not say,that against you
It is the judgement of this Court that the defendant,J. Huberman...
having found guilty of the crime of treason against the United States...
by the jury of this Court for the Southern District of Florida at Miami...
be committed to the custody of the United States Attorney General...
for imprisonment in an institution of the penitentiary type...
for a period of 20 years.
The defendant may be forthwith remanded to the custody of the U.S. Marshall.
Court is now adjourned.
Here she comes!
Just a minute,Miss Huberman! Look this way,would you,please?
We'd like a statement from you,Miss Huberman,about your father.
Do you think your father got what he deserved?
Are you pleased your father's going to pay the penalty...
for being a German worker?
Let us know if she tries to leave town.
Would you care to pause for some refreshments,Mr. Hopkins?
Alicia,were you really followed by a policeman?
- It sounds exciting. - I'm going to shoot it out with him.
Had enough.
Don't be silly. The important thing hasn't started yet.
Everybody down here's got a stuffed fish hanging on the wall.
- Where do they get them? - Never seen the fish.
How about you,handsome? Haven't I seen you somewhere before?
Oh,it doesn't matter. I like party-crashers.
He's not a party crasher. I brought him.
I wouldn't mind being followed by a cop.
I hate low,underhanded people like policemen pussy-footing after you.
Of course,I'm a marked women,no?
I am liable to blow up the Panama Canal any minute now.
- You want some ice in it? - No,thank you.
It's not becoming for a girl like you to be worried about cops.
- You won't be tomorrow? - Oh,really?
We sail at ten.
Really? We just sail away?
Show me a fish and I'll show you a liar.
What this party needs is a little glam treatment.
We'd better start breaking up. I have to be on board at nine.
One week in Havana and this whole thing will have blown over.
- Do you love me,Commodore? - You're a very beautiful woman.
I'll have another drink to appreciate that.
- Where are you going? - Fishing.
This time of night? You're mad.
- How about you,still drinking? - There's no fish,day or night.
You know something? I like you.
- I'll see you on board at 9 o'clock. - I've to think that over.
You don't have to pack. We'll pick up some things in Havana.
I think I'll have to leave him here to dry out,Alicia.
I'm sorry you have to go. It's been a perfectly hideous party.
- Goodnight. - Goodnight.
There's one more drink left.
- Shame about the ice. - What ice?
- Gone. - What's gone?
The ice.
Why do you like that song?
It's a lot of hooey.
There's nothing like a love song to give you a good laugh.
That's right.
- It's stuffy in here,isn't it. - It might be.
What about...
we have a picnic?
Outside?
Yeah,it's too stuffy in here for a picnic.
- Want to finish that? - Shame to leave it.
You're quite a boy.
- My car is outside. - Naturally.
- Want to go for a ride? - Very much.
What about your guests?
They'll crawl out under their own steam.
I'm going to drive. That's understood.
- Don' you need a coat? - You'll do me.
Wait a minute.
Let me put this on you,you might catch cold.
- How am I doing? - Not bad.
- Scared? - No.
- You're not scared of anything... - Not too much.
- This fog gets me. - It's your hair in your eyes.
What does the speedometer say?
Sixty-five.
I want to make it eighty and wipe that grin off your face.
I don't like gentlemen who grin at me.
A cop.
What?
A policeman is chasing us. look.
They make me sick.
He wants to talk to you.
Drunken driver.
A second offence. Now,I go to jail.
Whole family in jail! Who cares?
Having a time for yourself,aren't you?
People like you ought to be in bed.
- Drunk,huh? - Just a minute,officer.
No arguments,mister: you ain't got a leg to stand on.
Sorry,but you didn't speak up.
That's all right.
- Sure you can handle it? - No trouble.
Well,you ought to know.
Where's the ticket?
He didn't give me a ticket.
- What's your name? - Devlin.
You showed that cop something. He saluted you.
- Did he? - I saw him.
You double-crossing buzzard! You're a cop!
We'll argue that later.
- Get away from my car! - I'm going to take you home.
You're not going to take me home at all.
Move over!
Come on!
Get out of my car,Federal cop! For crashing my party!
Just like that buzzard with the glasses.
Give me alone. You're trailing me to get something out of me.
You going to calm down?
Good,now move over.
I'll kill you,I'm not going to let...
You better drink that.
Why is this necessary?
Go on,drink it!
Finish it!
Feel better?
What do you care how I feel?
You,you cop...
What's this all about,huh?
- What's your angle? - What angle?
- About last night. - Just wanted to be friends.
Friends,yes. So you could frame me,huh?
No,got a job for you.
Don't tell me,there's only...
There's only one job that you coppers would want me for.
- You can forget it,Mr... - Devlin.
- What? - Devlin.
I'm no stool-pigeon,Mr. Devlin.
My department authorised me to engage you to do some work in Brazil.
Go away! The whole thing bores me!
Some of the German gentry who were paying your father...
are working in Rio.
have you heard of IG Farben Enterprise?
I tell you not interested
Fabien has ambush in South America before the war
We're going to help the Brazilian government to smoke them out.
- My chief thinks that the daughter of... - Of a traitor?
Well,he thinks you might be valuable in the work.
They might sort of trust you.
And you could make up a little for your daddy's peculiarities.
- Why should I? - Patriotism.
That word gives me a pain. No,thank you.
I don't go for patriotism or patriots.
I could dispute that with you.
Waving the flag with one hand and picking pockets with the other's.
That's your patriotism.
You can have it.
We've had your bungalow wired for three months.
Conversation between John Huberman and daughter Alicia...
6:00 p.m. January 9,1946,at Miami Beach,Florida.
Some of the evidence that wasn't used at the trial.
- I don't want to hear that. - Relax,hard-boiled and listen.
it's for both of us. There's a lot of money in it,Alicia.
I told you before Christmas I wouldn't do it.
You can use your judgement. You can have anything you want.
- The work is easy. - I won't listen,father.
This is not your country,is it?
My mother was born here. We have American citizenship.
Where's your judgement? In your feelings you're German.
You've got to listen to me. You don't know what we stand for.
I know what you stand for,you and your murdering swine.
I've hated you ever since I found out.
My daughter don't talk to me like that.
- Don't ask me such a favour! - Alicia,keep your voice down.
I hate you all.
I love this country. Do you understand? I love it.
I'll see you all hang before I raise a finger against it!
Now go on,get out of here. Or so help me,I'll turn you in.
Don't ever come near me or speak to me about your rotten schemes.
That doesn't prove much. I didn't turn him in.
We didn't expect you to.
Well,what do you say?
Go away and leave me alone!
I've my own life to lead!
Good times,that's what I want. And laughs,with people I like.
And no underhanded cops who want to put me up in a shooting gallery...
but people of my own kind.
Who'll treat me right,and like me,and understand me.
Good morning,Alicia.
Oh,hello!
Thought you might need a hand. We're sailing with the tide,you know.
- Are you ready? - Yes.
- Don't tell me you've forgotten. - Almost.
I'll help you pack,although you really don't need anything.
- We've got everything on board. - Thank you,I'll pack myself.
We're moored at the hotel pier,you know the spot.
Yes.
You're a darling,sweetest girl I ever knew.
See you soon!
What about it? Plane leaves tomorrow morning early.
All right. You'd better tell him.
I'll tell her. See you later.
That's a very nice looking man.
You'll be seeing him in Rio.
Oh no,no. I won't be seeing any men in Rio.
Yes,you will. That's our boss,Paul Prescott.
- Did he say anything about the job? - No.
- No hints? - No.
He had some news about your father he picked up at the last stop.
- What about him? - He died this morning.
Oh!
- How? - Poison capsule.
- He did it himself? - Yes,in his cell.
Sorry.
I don't know why I should feel so bad.
When he told me a few years ago what he was...
everything went to pot,I didn't care what happened to me.
But now I remember how nice he was. How nice we both were.
Very nice.
It's a very curious feeling.
As if something had happened to me and not to him.
You see,I don't have to hate him anymore.
- Or myself. - We're coming into Rio.
Oh yes,we are.
I wonder if the embassy can get me a maid?
It's a nice apartment and I don't mind dusting and sweeping...
but I hate cooking.
-I ask - And while you're at it,find out when I go to work and what.
Yes,madam.
- Care to have something else? - Have another drink?
No,thank you,I've had enough.
I do. Whisky and soda.
Well,do you hear that?
I'm practically on the wagon. That's quite a change.
It's a phase.
You don't think a woman can change?
- Sure,a change is fun. For a while. - For a while?
What a rat you are,Devlin.
All right,you've been sober for eight days.
And as far as I know you've made no new conquests.
Well,that's something!
Eight days,practically white-washed.
I'm very happy,Devlin.
- Why don't you let me be happy? - Nobody's stopping you.
Why don't you give that copper's brain of yours a rest?
Every time you look at me I can see it running over its slogans:
Once a crook,always a crook. Once a tramp,always a tramp.
Go on,you can hold my hand. I won't blackmail you for it afterwards.
Scared?
I've always been scared of women. But I get over it.
Now you're scared of yourself.
You're afraid you'll fall in love with me.
That wouldn't be hard.
Now,careful,careful.
You enjoy making fun of me,don't you.
No,Devlin,I'm making fun of myself.
I'm pretending I'm a nice unspoilt child...
whose heart is full of daisies and buttercups.
Nice daydream. Then what?
I think I'll have another drink.
I thought you'd get around to it!
Make it a double!
- Whisky and soda,double. - Yes,sir.
Why won't you believe in me,Devlin?
Just a little.
Why won't you?
I know why you won't,Dev: you're sore.
You're sore because you've fallen for a little drunk you tailed in Miami.
And you don't like it,it makes you sick all over,doesn't it?
People will laugh at you. The invincible Devlin in love...
with someone who isn't worth even wasting the words on.
Poor Devlin,in love with a no-good gal. It must be awful,I'm sorry.
I assure you she's the perfect type for the job.
It's not the girl,it's this German scientist I'm worried about.
I simply question why we don't find some way of taking them into custody.
It' do no good,even if we arrested their leader,Alex Sebastian...
tomorrow another foreign man takes his place and the work goes on.
Yes,you're right.
I see,Captain Prescott,your method is the best way.
Well,she's good at making friends with gentlemen...
and we want somebody inside his house in his confidence.
- You've faith in this procedure? - Yes,with somebody on the side...
- Have you consulted the young lady? - No,not yet.
Our man Devlin just brought her down here the other day.
Now we're waiting for Sebastian to come back to Rio.
Has your man Devlin told her the nature of the work?
No,we haven't discussed it with him at all.
I can set your mind at rest about her.
You're sure of her political side?
Oh,yes.
Well,there is nothing to be lost if we proceed as you advise.
That's fine. I'll give Devlin his instructions right away.
it's nice out here!
Let's not go out for dinner. Let's stay here.
We have to eat.
We can eat here. I'll cook.
I thought you didn't like to cook.
No,I don't like to cook.
But I have a chicken in the ice-box and you're eating it.
What about all the washing up afterwards?
We'll eat it with our fingers.
Don't we need any plates?
Yes,one for you and one for me.
Do you mind if have dinner with you tonight?
I'd be delighted.
- Where are you going? - If we're going to stay in...
I've to telephone the hotel to see if there are any messages.
- You have to? - I have to.
- This is a very strange love affair. - Why?
Maybe the fact that you don't love me.
Hello?
Paris Hotel?
Reception desk?
This is T.R. Devlin. Are there any messages for me?
I don't love you. How do you know?
You haven't said anything.
Actions speak louder than words.
There is? Good,read it to me,please.
Thanks.
Prescott wants me over right away.
- Did he say what about? - No.
- Maybe it's our assignment. - Probably.
Do you want me to bring anything back?
Yes,what about a nice bottle of wine to celebrate?
What time shall I come back?
Seven o'clock.
- Goodbye. - Goodbye.
- What is it,Devlin,what's the matter? - I don't know if she'll do it.
What do you mean? You haven't discussed it with her,have you?
No,I didn't know what the job was until this moment.
- What do you mean she wouldn't do it? - She's not that type of woman.
I don't understand your attitude.
- Why do you think she won't do it? - Well,she's had no experience.
Come on,what experience does she lack,do you think?
She's never been trained for that... They'll see through her.
Alicia Huberman was chosen...
not only because her father gives her an ideal background...
but because Sebastian knows her.
Yes.
He was once in love with her.
Oh,I didn't know that.
I don't know why we're arguing about petty things like this.
We've got important work to do.
Sebastian's house is a cover-up. whatever Fabien group up to here.
- We've got to get Miss Huberman inside and find out
what's going on there. - yeah that's right
I' think you'd better go back to Miss Huberman and explain it to her.
- I... - What is it?
Nothing,sir.
I thought you were going to say something.
How is the meeting to be arranged?
We've discussed that. The riding club would be the best place.
Sebastian usually rides there in the mornings.
The rest is up to you and Miss Huberman.
- Okay,Devlin,that's all. - All right.
- Dev,is that you? - Huh?
I'm glad you're late.
This chicken took longer than I expected.
What did they say?
I hope it isn't done too much. It caught fire once.
I think it's better if I cut it up out here.
Unless you want a half of one for yourself.
We're going to have knives and forks after all.
I've decided we're going to eat in style.
Marriage must be wonderful with this sort of thing going on everyday.
I wonder if it's too cold out here.
Maybe we should eat inside.
Hasn't something like this happened before?
What's the matter?
Don't look so tense. Troubles?
Well,I think you'd better tell Mamma what's going on.
All this secrecy's going to ruin my little dinner.
Come on,Mr. D.,what is darkening your brow?
- After dinner. - No,now.
I'll make it easy for you.
The time has come when you must tell me...
you have a wife and two adorable children.
And this madness between us can't go on any longer.
I bet you've heard that line often enough.
Right below the belt every time.
That isn't fair,Dev.
Skip it.
We've other things to talk about. We've got a job.
Oh,so,there's a job.
You remember a man named Sebastian?
- Alex Sebastian? - Yes.
One of my father's friends,yes.
He had quite a crush on you.
I wasn't very responsive.
He's here at the head of a large German business concern.
- His family always had money. - He's part of the combine that...
built up the German war machine and wants to keep it going.
- Something big? - It has all the earmarks of being it!
We've to contact him.
Go on,let's have all of it.
We're meeting him tomorrow. The rest is up to you.
You've got to work on him and land him.
Mata Hari! She makes love for papers.
There are no papers.
You'll land him,Find out what's going on inside his house...
what the group around him is up to and report to us.
I suppose you knew about this pretty little job of mine all the time.
No,I only just found out about it.
Well,did you say anything?
I mean,that maybe I wasn't the girl for such shenanigans?
I figured that was up to you. If you'd care to back out...
I suppose you told them Alicia Huberman...
will have this Sebastian eating out of her hand in a couple of weeks.
She's good at that,always was.
I didn't say anything.
Not a word for that little love-sick lady you left an hour ago.
I told you that's the assignment.
Well now,don't get sore,Dev.
I'm only fishing for a little bird-call from my dream man.
One little remark such as:
How dare you gentlemen suggest that Alicia Huberman...
the new Miss Huberman,be submitted to so ugly a fate?
That's not funny.
- Do you want me to take the job? - You're answering for yourself.
- I'm asking you. - It's up to you.
Not a peep.
Darling,what you didn't tell them,tell me.
That you believe I'm nice,that I love you and I'll never change back.
I'm waiting for your answer.
What a little pal you are.
Never believing me,huh?
Not a word of faith.
Just down the drain with Alicia,that's where she belongs.
Oh,Dev,Dev!
When do I go to work for Uncle Sam?
Tomorrow morning.
We shouldn't have had this out here. It's all cold now.
What are you looking for?
I had a bottle of champagne. I must have left it somewhere.
In case you're asked,I'm with Pan American Airways.
- As Devlin? - Yes,Public Relations Officer.
Anything else?
No,except we met on the plane coming in from Miami.
The less detail the better.
- Are you sure that's him? - Yes.
We'll go by him easy and let him spot you. Come on.
I guess I'm the girl nobody remembers.
- Was it Sebastian? - Yes.
We'll stick around: give him another chance.
My dear Alicia,will you forgive me for being late?
Last minute conference at the office. You got my message?
- Yes,it's all right,Alex. - It was sweet of you to wait.
- I was afraid you might run off. - Oh,I'm not that easily put off.
I was too anxious to meet you again.
You know,I'm tired.
The worst thing about business is it makes you feel old and look old.
You seem to have escaped all of that.
Four years of dullness and disintegration.
Awful!
Alex,you look younger than you did in Washington.
It's a temporary improvement,entirely due to your presence.
You always affected me like a tonic.
But perhaps now with you here in Rio...
unless you insist on running away from me again...
- Oh,would you like another drink? - Yes,thank you.
Two martinis.
Do you know him?
No,I don't think so,but he seems familiar.
Captain Prescott,intelligence man.
He's down here as part of the Washington espionage.
The American Embassy's loaded with them.
Really?
He's really handsome,isn't he?
I'm allergic to American agents.
Their fine points don't particularly appeal to me.
They've bothered you since you came down?
No,no,not yet.
They were troublesome in Miami?
Yes,that's why I left right after the trial:
to get away from their snooping.
I wondered why you left your father.
He insisted. He was so unselfish.
He kept worrying about me and begging me to leave.
I had no idea he was going to die.
Many things have died for all of us. We mustn't let our spirit die with them.
Perhaps I can help you to forget. I'd like to.
Well,it's odd...
but I feel at home with you.
You know,my dear...
I knew this was going to happen.
I knew when we met the other day...
that if I... saw you again...
I'd feel what I used to for you.
The same hunger.
You're so lovely,my dear.
Now I'm going to make a fool of myself again.
There's someone else,of course. Who is it this time?
That Mr Devlin you were with?
There is no-one.
He seemed attentive.
Mr. Devlin has pestered me with his attentiveness ever since I arrived...
I met him on the plane from Miami.
You made a pretty couple.
Oh,Alex! Mr. Devlin doesn't interest me.
I was so Ionely that day...
I could have gone riding with Peter Rabbit.
You'll let me help your Ioneliness?
You're very sweet to forget what a brat I was once.
My dear,I shall test out your repentance.
At once.
Will you have dinner with me again tomorrow night?
- Thank you very much. - My house?
Yes,how nice.
My mother's giving a dinner party.
- She won't mind an extra guest? - An old friend is never an extra guest.
- Well,shall we order now? - Yes,yes,I'm starved.
Let's see,what shall we have for our first dinner together?
- Good evening. - Very good.
Yes,yes,isn't it?
I'd like you to wear these. They're rented for the occasion.
- Would you help me please,I can't... - What? Yes,certainly.
Thank you.
- So,the old boy knew me,eh? - He thought you were very handsome.
Well,you don't say. Sorry,I'm not going with you.
Oh,Dev will pick those up later.
Try to memorise the names of all the people you see there tonight.
The men,I mean.
And get their nationalities. That's very important.
You mean the Germans? That won't be difficult for me.
I suggest you don't ask any questions. Just use your eyes and ears.
They're a keen and desperate bunch. Don't underestimate them.
Thanks for your instructions. Good evening.
By the way,unless you have something very urgent to report...
I suggest you two keep shy of each other for the next few days.
Just in case Sebastian's people want to check on you after your visit.
- I understand. - Good luck.
- Goodnight. - Goodnight.
Good evening. I'm Miss Huberman,would you tell Mr. Sebastian I'm here?
- Miss Huberman? - Yes.
Please forgive me for keeping you waiting.
Not at all.
You resemble your father very much. I'm Alex's mother.
I knew when I saw you.
Alex has always admired you. Now,at last,I know why.
You're very kind.
We thought unusual that you did not testify at your father's trial.
He didn't want me to.
He refused to let his lawyers call me on the stand.
I wonder why?
Hello! Alicia!
I'm so glad!
- You met my mother. - Yes,we just met.
You didn't meet Alicia when we were in Washington,did you mother?
- I don't know where you were then? - I think we should join our guests.
- May I take your robe? - Thank you.
Miss Huberman,may I present Eric Mathis?
- How do you do? - How do you do?
William Rothman.
How do you do?
Very honoured.
Emil Hupka.
How do you do?
Delighted.
And Mr. Nair.
And Dr. Anderson.
Dr. Anderson.
it gives me great pleasure.
Dr. Anderson is our Guest of Honour tonight.
You mustn't bore Miss Huberman with discourses on science.
Not before dinner,anyway.
Dinner is served,Madame.
Dr. Anderson,you will sit beside me,over there.
Eric,you will sit next to Miss Huberman.
You have just come from Spain,Senora?
A few weeks ago. It seems ages.
Travel does not mean anything anymore,it goes so swiftly.
One has the feeling of not going anywhere.
I suppose we can expect the rocket ships...
to be carrying us across the oceans very soon.
We can expect many strange things.
- Did you see a good movie,Eric? - No,I was disappointed.
It must have been a comedy. Eric loves to go to the movies to cry.
He's very sentimental.
I'm afraid,gentlemen,that something must be done about Emil.
I don't know.
It was an understandable slip: the man was tired.
No,it's a very dangerous slip.
It's not the first one. There have been several other lapses.
There'll be more,if we permit it.
That's bad,that's very bad!
I think,gentlemen,you can leave it to me to find some way.
When you drive up to Metropolis,the road winds quite a bit.
It is very high. There are some very awkward turns.
I'm sure I'll not have any difficulty...
in getting Emil to give me a lift in his car.
It's quite a trick to jump clear.
I'll just have to be careful,that is all.
Turned my ankle the last time.
Madame says will you join the others or will you take your coffee in here?
I think we'll take coffee in here,Emil.
I'm very sorry gentlemen,to make such an exhibition.
Oh,nonsense!
We all have nerves!
You've been overworking.
Don't you think so,Rothman?
You need a rest.
Your health is very important to us.
That's very considerate. I am very tired.
Now,I think perhaps if you'll make my pardon to the ladies,Alex...
for my leaving so early,then I go...
I think maybe,Emil,it would be better if I came with you.
If you try to drive yourself all the way up to Metropolis...
it might be too much for you.
I shall drive you.
No!
It'd be too much for you all that way. That's too much to ask.
Nonsense,I'd love to go!
Come on,Emil.
Goodnight,gentlemen.
Goodnight,Alex.
I hope you feel better in the morning,Emil.
Thank you,and I'm very sorry to make a scene before strangers.
Very sorry.
Thank you,Alex,for an excellent dinner.
And please tell your mother from me that the desert was superb.
Miss Huberman has been gone a long time.
Is it necessary for you to address Alicia as Miss Huberman?
I do wish you'd be a little more cordial to her.
Really? I thought I was behaving very well.
Has she been complaining about me?
- No,no. - I'm grateful.
You might smile at her.
Wouldn't it be a little too much if we both grinned at her like idiots?
Please,mother,I want to enjoy myself.
Is it so boring to sit with me alone?
Not at all,not at all.
- Hello! - Hello!
- I thought I saw you. - How are you?
Fine thanks. Great turn out,isn't it?
Yes.
- Where are they? - In a box in the stand.
I don't think they can see us,Alex and his mother.
Don't telephone me any more. Just rely on my popping up.
- Can you hear me? - Sure,go ahead.
- Have you heard of Dr. Anderson? - No.
He's some kind of a scientist: kind face,sixty years old,grey hair.
Deep crease in the forehead.
- Tall or short? - Short.
- Emil Hupka,heard of him? - No.
He made quite a scene about a wine bottle the other night.
Didn't like the vintage?
He seemed to think there was something else in the bottle.
- Was there? - No,it was wine. We drank it.
- Has he pulled anything since? - Haven't seen him since.
Anything else?
Nothing important.
Just a minor item,but you may want it for the record.
What is it?
You can add Sebastian's name to my list of playmates.
Pretty fast work.
- That's what you wanted,wasn't it? - Skip it.
- Are you betting on this race? - No.
Alex says number ten is sure to win. He knows the owner.
Thanks for the tip.
He says they've been holding him back all season...
I can't help recalling some of your remarks about being a new woman.
Daisies and buttercups,wasn't it?
Oh,you idiot! What are you sore about?
- You knew very well what I was doing. - Did I?
You could have stopped me with one word,but you threw me at him.
I threw you at nobody.
Didn't you tell me to go ahead?
A man doesn't tell a woman what to do. She tells herself.
I almost believed in that little hokey-pokey miracle of yours...
that a woman like you could ever change her spots.
Oh,you're rotten!
That's why I didn't try to stop you. The answer had to come from you.
- I see,some kind of love test. - That's right.
You never believed in me anyway...
Lucky for both of us I didn't. It'd have been pretty if I'd believed.
If I'd figure: she'll never be able to go through with this.
She can make it over by love.
If you only once had said that you loved me.
You chalked up another boyfriend that's all,no harm done.
I hate you!
There's no occasion to. You're doing a good work.
Number ten's out in front.
Looks as if Sebastian knows how to pick them.
Is that all you have to say to me?
Dry your eyes,baby,it's out of character.
Except keep on your toes. It's a tough job we're on.
Snap out of it,here comes dreamboat.
Hello,Alex! It was so exciting,a beautiful horse.
- Do you remember Mr. Devlin,Alex? - How do you do?
Hello,Alicia tells me you had a bet on number ten.
Sorry I didn't get the tip earlier. So long.
See you sometime,Dev.
It was a wonderful race. Did you have much money on the winner?
I didn't see the race,
I thought I saw you looking through your field glasses.
I was watching you and your friend,Mr. Devlin.
I suppose that's why you left my mother and me.
- You both had an appointment... - Don't be absurd!
I met him purely by accident.
You didn't seem very anxious to get away from him.
- Oh,he's just... - I watched you.
I thought maybe you were in love with him.
Don't talk like that. I detest him.
Really? He's very good-Iooking.
Alex...
I've told you before,Mr. Devlin doesn't mean a thing to me.
I'd like to be convinced.
Would you maybe care to convince me,Alicia...
that Mr. Devlin means nothing to you?
...pleased to hear,Sr. Barbosa,that our little theatrical plan is working.
We've got hold of something concrete for a change.
I'm delighted,gentlemen. What is it?
Professor Otto Rensler is working here in Brazil.
One of Germany's scientific wizards.
I didn't know he was here.
He's living and experimenting in Sebastian's house.
They call him Doctor Anderson.
Entre!
Excuse me,sir.
Miss Huberman wishes to see Captain Prescott or Mr. Devlin.
- Do you mean she's here? - Yes,sir.
- Well,show her in,Hubero. - Yes,sir.
I don't like this. I don't like her coming here.
She's had me worried for some time. A woman of that sort.
What sort is that,Mr. Beardsley?
I don't think any of us have any illusions about her character.
Not at all. Not in the slightest.
Miss Huberman is first,last and always not a lady.
She may be risking her life...
but when it comes to being a lady...
she doesn't hold a candle to your wife,sir...
sitting in Washington...
playing bridge with three other ladies of great honour and virtue.
- Take it easy,Dev. - Sorry.
I think those remarks about my wife are uncalled for.
Withdrawn. Apologise,sir.
- How do you do,Miss Huberman? - How do you do?
- This is Mr. Beardsley and Sr. Julio Barbosa. Sit down? - thake you
You have the esteem of my government
But we are worried about your visiting this office.
I promise not to break the rules again...
but I need some advice and I couldn't find Mr. Devlin.
In fact,I need it before lunch.
Well,has something happened?
Yes,something rather confusing.
Mr. Sebastian has asked me to marry him.
- What? - Well,well.
He wants me to marry him right away. I 'm to give him my answer at lunch.
I don't know what the department might think about such a step?
Are you willing to go this far for us?
Yes,if you wish.
What do you think of this,Devlin?
I think it's a useful idea.
You know the situation better than any of us.
May I ask what inspired Alex Sebastian to go this far?
He's in love with me.
And he thinks you're in love with him?
Yes,that's what he thinks.
Gentlemen,it's the cream of the chest.
Then,it's all right?
Well,yes,I'd say so.
Of course,it's a perfect marriage for us.
There's only one thing: won't it delay us a bit?
What do you mean?
Mr. Sebastian is a very romantic fellow.
Isn't he,Alicia?
Yes.
Then,he'll probably want to take his bride away for a long honeymoon.
- Won't that hold us up? - Devlin's got a point here.
I don't know,I think we can rely on Miss Huberman...
to get back into the house quickly.
Yes,I think I can manage that.
Well,everything seems to be nicely arranged.
I don't think you need me here anymore,do you,Captain Prescott?
I do want to thank you,Miss Huberman very much.
So far everything has been managed with great intelligence.
Yes,thank you very much.
Are you sure she didn't come down here to see you?
To capture the rich Alexander Sebastian for a husband?
Don't be absurd. She didn't even know I was here.
Well,we'll discuss it more fully tonight.
We'll not discuss it tonight.
All these carping questions are the expression of your jealousy.
You've always been jealous of any woman I've ever shown any interest in.
In this case,there is nothing more to discuss.
You mean you're going ahead with this marriage?
I mean that the wedding will be next week.
It will be private.
We shall both be pleased to have you present,if you wish.
- Good evening,sir. - Good evening.
- Madam! - Good evening,Joseph.
It doesn't look very cheerful here.
I'm sorry,Madame Sebastian wasn't certain you would be back tonight.
Why not? I telegraphed her.
Madame Sebastian said we were all to retire,sir.
Where is my mother?
Madame Sebastian went to bed very early,sir.
I'm sorry,dear,I'm afraid this isn't a very bright homecoming.
- That's all right,Alex. - What shall we do?
Shall we have Joseph arrange a little food for us?
Not unless you want to. I'm rather tired myself.
We'll go right up,then.
- Goodnight,Joseph. - Goodnight,Madam.
I'd like to have all my dresses put out on the beds here.
Don't hang anything up. I like to know where everything goes.
Joseph,would you've the closets aired?
Yes,Madame.
Oh,this isn't very large. I'll need more room.
- This door is locked. - That's used for a storeroom,Madame.
- Oh,may I have the key? - I do not have the keys,Madame.
Where are they?
Madame Sebastian has charge of all the house keys.
Do you know where Mr. Sebastian is?
I think he's having a business meeting in the study,Madame.
I miss Hupka. He was a first-class metallurgist.
Klieten is just as good.
Such is your opinion.
- But I don't want to criticise. - What were you asking?
Oh,you want a report,a written report.
Well,my friends,my work is done.
You've been successful?
Yes.
- Oh,I'm very sorry. - Oh,no,come on in.
I'm sorry to interrupt you. I didn't know you were busy.
Some of the closets are locked. Could you give me the keys?
I'm sorry. I'd forgotten about the keys.
Of course,I'll get them for you at once.
I'll bring the keys to you right away,my dear.
Mother,Mother!
Well,there they are.
I'm afraid I'm going to be busy for the rest of the morning.
- See you at lunch. - Thank you,dear.
Mr. Sebastian has the keys for this,Madame.
It's the wine cellar.
Then,the wince cellar's the obvious place to look.
- Alex has the key to that. - Then get it from him.
Get it. Yes,how?
Don't you leave near him?
What do I look for if I get the key?
You look for a bottle of wine,like the one that rattled that fellow.
All the bottles look alike to me. I'm no mastermind.
You're doing all right.
It's no fun,Dev.
Too late for that now,isn't it?
Look,why don't you persuade your husband to throw a large shindig...
so he can introduce his bride to Rio society say sometime next week?
Why?
Consider me invited.
I'll try to find out about that wine cellar business.
I don't think my husband is interested in entertaining just yet.
The honeymoon isn't over,eh?
Don't underestimate your charms,Mrs. Sebastian,you can handle it.
It's not going to be so easy about you. He thinks you're in love with me.
Tell him if you invited me to the house and saw how happily married you were...
the horrid passion I have for you might be torn out of me.
That sounds very logical.
Good,next week then. And get the key.
I have to fly up to Bel Air. But I'll be back in time.
All right,I'll be looking forward to seeing you.
It's always a pleasure meeting you,Madame.
I'm surprised Mr. Devlin coming tonight.
I don't blame anyone for being in love with you,darling.
I just hope that nothing will happen to give him any false impression.
I'll be with you in a minute.
Darling.
It's not that I don't trust you,but when you're in love at my age...
every man that looks at your woman is a menace.
Will you forgive me for even talking aboutit?
I'm very contrite.
I think we might join the rest of the party now.
I think all our guests are here.
Where can I find Madame Sebastian?
- Try the door,sir. - Thanks.
- Hello,Dev. - Good evening.
- You haven't seen the house? - No,it's quite a jolly little cottage.
- Let me show you around the place. - Later. His nibs is on the trail.
- Devlin,glad to see you. - Good night.
It was kind of your bride to invite me.
We both invite you,Mr. Devlin.
Will you see our guest is fed,my dear? And amused...
Oh,excuse me.
Madame Esterich,I'm so glad to see you.
- It's not going to be easy. - Why?
He's quite sensitive about you. He's going to watch us like a hawk.
Yes,he's rather jealous of anyone.
Where did you get the key? Off his chain?
Yes.
Let's hope the liquor doesn't run out and start him down the cellar for more.
- I hadn't thought about that. - Quite a point.
Thank you.
Mr. Devlin,how nice! You remember me?
Senora Ortiz.
How sweet,young men usually have short memories.
Here's something I adore: champagne.
Oh,may I?
- Joseph? - Madame?
Do you think you have enough champagne for the rest of the evening?
I don't know,Madame. I hope so.
- Enjoying yourself,Mr. Devlin? - Very much,thank you.
There are so many things I'd like to ask about the States.
I haven't heard anything for a long time.
I'll be glad to tell you. Will you excuse me,Senora Ortiz?
I don't mind,certainly!
- We'd better hurry. - Lots of time.
No,Joseph might have to ask Alex for more wine.
He's running out faster than he thought.
I'm sorry to hear that.
- Is he watching? - Yes.
You'd better go out into the garden and wait around the back of the house.
I'll show you the wine cellar door.
- Nice party,isn't it? - It's a wonderful party.
I think you've done it wonderfully well.
I'm very proud. Mr. Devlin bothering you much?
No,darling. He's trying to drown his sorrows.
Excuse me,think I'll ask the orchestra to play some Brazilian music.
They've played waltzes all evening.
All right,dear.
- That's the door. - Right.
I'll keep the garden door open and I'll tell you if anything happens.
What's happened?
Look,Vintage sand.
We've got to leave things as we found them.
Help me find a bottle of wine with the same label as these others.
- It isn't really sand,is it? - I think it's some kind of metal ore.
- This is a bit weird. - I'm terrified.
Just pretend you're a janitor. Janitors are never terrified.
I have a feeling we're very slow.
We're on schedule. Take it easy.
I can hear someone coming.
Oh,that'll be nice.
Think if he comes down with Joseph.
Unfortunate.
Someone is coming.
It's Alex. He's seen us.
Wait a minute. I'm going to kiss you.
- No,he'll only think... - That's what I want him to think.
You better stay upstairs,they may need you.
Yes,sir.
Oh,Dev,Dev!
Push me away!
I'm sorry to intrude on this tender scene.
I couldn't help what happened: he's been drinking.
So,he carried you down here.
Please,Alex!
- You love him. - No,of course not. Please go.
For what it's worth,as an apology,your wife is telling the truth.
I knew her before you,I loved here before you...
but I wasn't as lucky as you.
Sorry,Alicia.
- Please,go. - Goodnight.
Alex,don't be foolish. I came down here...
because he threatened to make a scene unless I'd see him alone.
He kissed you.
I couldn't stop him.
We'll talk about it later. Your guests are upstairs.
Will you please go to them?
Mr. Devlin,are you going so soon?
Yes,I'm afraid I have to be up early in the morning.
Thank you and goodnight.
- Joseph? - Yes,sir.
- We can go down for the wine now. - Yes,sir.
Joseph,I don't think we need to give them any more champagne.
- We still have some upstairs. - Yes,sir.
- There's whisky and the wine. - Yes,sir.
Well,I think we'll give them that.
I'm sorry about what happened,Alex.
My dear,I shall never forgive myself for behaving like a schoolboy.
- Then you believe me? - Of course.
- It isn't worth mentioning again. - Thank you.
- Are you coming up? - Not for a little while.
Dr. Anderson's waiting for me in the study.
Sleep well.
It was a very successful party.
- Goodnight,then. - Goodnight.
Thanks for being so nice.
Mother!
Why are you up so early?
I need your help.
Something is wrong?
A great deal,Alicia.
I have expected it.
I knew,I knew!
What is it? Mr. Devlin?
No.
I'm married to an American agent.
Yes,it's easy to see now.
I knew but I didn't see.
They picked her because of her father.
I must have been insane,mad. Behaved like an idiot.
To believe in her with her clinging kisses!
Stop wallowing in your foul memories.
Well,what do I do?
There's nothing to do. I'm done,finished.
- They'll find out. - They won't find out.
They'll find out what I'm married to.
Look what they did to Emil Hupka. Emil,who did nothing.
And I betrayed them. I bungled and there's no excuse.
I'd do the same myself: kill the fool that betrayed them.
- There's no need for them to find out. - Mathis is very sharp.
He dislikes you,but his criticism of your talents wouldn't
go that far to image that you're married to an American agent.
We are protected by the enormity of you stupidity for a time.
- Listen,I'll take care of her myself. - No,not in that way.
I stood looking at her while she was asleep and I could have...
Quiet,Alex!
You're almost as impetuous I as before your wedding.
You barred me from that episode. Let me arrange this one.
Listen to me. No-one must know what she is.
There must be no suspicion of her,of you,of me.
She must be allowed to move about freely.
But she will be on a leash.
She will learn nothing further to inform.
She must go,but it must happen slowly.
If she could become ill,and remain ill for a time,until...
Drink you coffee,darling,it's getting cold.
Are you going out this afternoon,Alex?
No,my dear,I've some letters to write. What are you going to do?
Oh,I just have a little shopping.
I'd like to go to the imperial. Maybe I'll go to Cosmo's...
and see if they've any new books in from New York.
If you're going down there,will you go into Sisacruz for me...
and see if my cigars have arrived?
Should be about a thousand.
If they've,ask them to keep them in the humidor for me.
Anything wrong?
No,the light bothers me.
I have a bit of a headache,would you mind...
- yes,I think we can fix that. - Thank you.
Some people get too much sun down here,you must be careful.
I think you can be very proud of yourself.
That sand that Devlin brought in shows uranium ore.
So now we know what we're driving at.
Your job from now on will be to help us find out where that sand comes from.
The location of the uranium deposit is of vast importance and...
we're putting quite a few people on it.
But I think you'll be of great help.
All right.
But that isn't the main reason why I asked you to come up here.
- No? - No,I wanted to tell you...
that I'm going to change your contact in about a week.
Mr. Devlin's been transferred to Spain.
To Spain?
- Does Mr. Devlin know that? - Oh yes,he asked for the transfer.
Why?
I guess he thought he was going to stale here.
Oh,he wants to leave Rio.
He thought he'd find Spain more interesting.
Yes,I imagine it would be. There really isn't very much...
for a brainy fellow like Mr. Devlin to do in Rio any more.
Well,of course,it is more or less routine now.
In the meantime I'm to report to Mr. Devlin as usual.
Yes,he'll be here until the new man arrives.
Thank you,Captain Prescott,I'll keep my ears wide open.
- Good bye. - Good bye.
Oh,and... go easy on that sun,eh?
Darling,what is it?
I don't know.
- Are you in pain? - Yes,I'm so dizzy.
What happened to her?
We were walking and she was stricken suddenly.
I'll be all right. Let's go inside.
I'm sorry I couldn't make it on time.
Well,it gets a bit Ionely squatting on a bench all day.
Yes,Rio can be a very dull town.
What's new?
Nothing. What's new of you?
Nothing.
Any domestic troubles about the other night?
No.
Any footprints in that sand yet?
No,nothing yet.
Just a social visit,huh?
A little fresh air helps.
You don't look so hot.
- Well - Sick?
No. Hangover.
That's news. Back to the bottle again,huh?
Sort of lightens my chores.
- Big party? - Just the family circle.
Sounds quite jolly.
it helps life in a dull town.
You ought to take it easy on that liquor.
Don't you find Rio a little hard to take,too?
Not a bad town.
You look all mashed up: must have been quite an evening.
Yes,it was.
Well,if you want to play it that way,go on have fun.
No reason why you shouldn't.
That's right,Dev. Here's something that belongs to you.
I should have given it to you sooner.
- What is it? - The scarf you lent me once in Miami.
Cleaning house,huh?
Yeah...
Well,goodbye,Dev.
What do you mean,goodbye?
Nothing,just goodbye.
Fresh air isn't as good for a hangover as I thought.
Sit down,you're still tight.
I don't want to.
Where are you going?
Back home.
You're not taking care of yourself,Alicia.
Oh,I feel much better.
You look like something awful.
Circles under the eyes...
My dear child,you must have a doctor find out...
what is the matter with you.
I never go near doctors.
They always want to cart you off to a hospital.
Maybe you belong in a hospital.
Tell me when did you first feel sick?
I don't remember,maybe the party,I think.
I still think a sea trip...
would be much better for you darling nor doctors or hospitals.
A little cruise somewhere. Maybe Spain?
Put the roses back in your cheeks,my sweet.
I don't think so. I don't care much for boats.
We could go together,my dear.
If you could bear to leave Alex behind for a few weeks.
I think I prefer Alex to a case of seasickness.
I always get seasick.
Then you might like the mountains.
The air's fresh and pure and...
- I'm gong next week. - Oh,you're leaving?
I'm sorry,I'll miss you.
Yes,I'm delaying my work too long.
If you'll come with me,the mountains won't make you seasick.
And the Aimress mountains are beautiful,covered with flowers...
What Alicia needs is rest,not mountain climbing.
I've heard about the Aimress.
Did you? Really?
Yes,about the beautiful little native towns.
Are you going to Leopoldina?
- No,no,I'm going to Santa Ma... - Care for some more brandy,Otto?
No,thanks.
I never drink more than one brandy and even this is sometimes too much.
I'll just finish my coffee.
- No,that is not your... - That's Alicia's...
I'm sorry,
Yeah,perhaps Alex is right,my dear child.
When you are young,rest is the best doctor.
if you lie still for a few days...
reading,relaxing,forgetting all your troubles...
it might be as well as a medicinal ocean air.
And when I come back you will be all well...
making us all very happy once more.
Excuse me,I want to go to bed,I feel...
Pain again,darling?
Sorry to complain again.
Shall I take you up to your room?
May I help you,my dear? Some hot water,maybe?
No,no,please don't bother.
I'll be all right.
If she's no better in the morning,I insist you call a doctor.
I don't like the way she looks.
I'm worried about her.
Alicia! Joseph!
Joseph! Help me with her,will you?
- You must take her up to bed. - Yes,up to her room.
Come on,my dear.
I told you she was sick.
Now,come on,don't excite yourself. Be quiet.
No,no,go away! No! No!
The attack's come so suddenly! I'm sure is not serious.
We must get a doctor. The poor child is suffering so much.
I'll call the hospital. I'll get Doctor Lisard.
Don't worry,dear Otto. We'll get a doctor,a good one.
We'll take the best care of her.
Joseph,disconnect the telephone.
Madame must have absolute quiet.
Take it out of the room,Joseph.
Five days,eh?
Say,that must be quite a binge she's on.
I don't think so.
You said she was drinking last week,drunk when you saw her.
- But I've had time to think it over. - Think what over.
That drinking of hers. I don't believe it.
Why should she lie to you about that?
I don't know.
But she wasn't drunk,she was sick.
Maybe that's why she hasn't shown up.
She looked like the ragged end of nowhere.
- It still sounds like a hangover to me. - Well,I'm going to pay her a call.
Wait a minute! I don't want you to mess things up.
We hope to close this case down in a few days.
I won't mess anything up.
Just a social call. I'm a friend of the family.
All right,go ahead if you want to. But don't take any chances.
And call me up when you get back!
I'll do that!
Good evening,sir.
Good evening. Family home tonight?
Yes,sir.
Would you mind telling Mr. Sebastian that Mr. Devlin is here?
- What is it,Joseph? - I'm sorry,sir,but...
since Mr. Sebastian asked me not to disturb him...
Asleep?
No sir,he's in the study with some business associates.
- How long will he be tied up? - I don't know,sir.
- Is Mrs. Sebastian home? - Yes,sir.
- Would you mind telling her? - I'm afraid I can't,sir.
Why not?
Mrs. Sebastian is very ill and confined to her bed.
I'm sorry to hear that.
- How long has she been ill? - A week.
- Has she had a doctor? - I think so,sir.
We're all very concerned about her.
If you'll wait here,Mr. Devlin,I'll tell Mr. Sebastian.
Right.
- Excuse me,sir? - What is it,Joseph?
Mr. Devlin to see you,sir.
Tell him I'll be with him in a minute,will you?
Yes,sir.
Go on,professor. This sounds serious to me.
To me,also.
- What happened Monday? - Same thing.
When I left the bank a man was following me.
This morning when I went to the ticket office...
the same man came inside and stood beside me.
Alicia!
Dev!
Alicia,what's wrong with you?
I'm so glad you came.
I had to. I couldn't stand any more.
Waiting and worrying about you.
It wasn't a hangover you had that day.
You were sick then. What is it?
Yes,I was sick then.
What's wrong with you,Alicia?
- Oh,Dev. - What is it dear? What's wrong?
They're poisoning me. I couldn't get away from them.
I tried,but it was too weak.
How long?
Since the party.
Alex and his mother found out.
You want to try to sit up.
Sit up. I've got to get you out of here.
I thought you had gone.
No,I had to see you once to speak my piece.
I was getting out because I love you.
I couldn't bear seeing you and him together.
Oh,you love me! Why didn't you tell me before?
I know,but I couldn't see straight or think straight.
I was a fat-headed guy full of pain. It tore me up not having you.
Oh,you love me! You love me!
Long ago. All the time since the beginning.
Here,put on your robe.
- Come on. - Yes.
Try to stand up.
Dev,I'm afraid,I can't make it because they gave me pills to sleep.
Keep away. Keep talking.
- Have you got a coat? - In the closet.
They didn't want the others to know about me.
Keep talking.
Come on. What happened?
- Alex found out. - And the others haven't?
They'd kill him if they knew. They killed Emil.
Are you in pain?
I don't know,the pills...
Give me your feet...
Say it again. It keeps me awake.
I love you.
Stand up! Stand up!
Come on,wake up! Talk!
- Dr. Anderson... - Go on,go on.
Walk! Talk!
The sand comes from the Aimress mountains.
We'll find it.
From a town,Santa Ma... something.
Good girl. We'll take care of it later.
- Come on,keep walking! - I'm afraid,Dev.
They're all in the house. We can't make it.
Don't ever leave me.
You'll never get rid of me again.
I'll never try to.
Brace up. Here he comes.
What are you doing,Alicia? What is this,Mr. Devlin?
I'm taking her to the hospital to get the poison out of her.
Poison?
Would you like your friends downstairs to know?
I'm taking her back to her room.
No,I'll raise quite a rumpus if you try.
Alex!
- He knows? - Yes.
What is happening,Alex?
Alicia!
- She's worse? - Yes.
All right,dear,we're going.
You haven't forgotten what they did to Emil,have you Sebastian?
Help him,Alex.
I'm glad you have a head on you,Madame.
I'm not afraid to die.
You've got your chance,here and now.
Tell them who she is.
Need any help,Alex?
- No,we can handle her. - Where are you taking her?
You answer that one,Sebastian.
To the hospital.
Alex,talk to them,quick!
I'm glad she's going.
You should not have waited so long,Alex.
What am I going to do,start shooting?
Hold on,darling,you've only got about twenty yards to go.
What happened,Alex?
Oh,she collapsed.
Mr. Devlin heard her scream when he was waiting for me.
Come on,Alicia.
Yes,I telephoned the hospital as soon as I saw how she was.
- You have a car,Mr. Devlin? - In front.
Your hat,Alex.
You're going with them,Anna?
No,Alex will call me up. I'll wait here.
The sooner the doctor sees her...
Poor child!
- How do you feel? - Bit dizzy.
- Take some deep breaths. - Hurry,hurry.
- Just a minute,I must sit with her. - No room,Sebastian.
- You must take me,they're watching! - That's your headache.
Please take me! Please,please!
There is no telephone in her room to call the hospital.
Alex,will you come in,please? I wish to talk to you.
end